relicnews.com 2018-09-12

# SEGA UK - Privacy Policy | SEGA

Effective Date, 17 May 2018

## **Introduction**

SEGA Europe Limited, its subsidiaries and affiliates (together “ **SEGA** ”, individually a “ **SEGA** **Entity** ”) are committed to protecting the privacy and security of your personal information. SEGA collects different types of information from you when you use our mobile, online and downloadable products and services (" **Products** ").

This Privacy Policy explains how we collect, use and protect your personal information when you use our Products.

By using our Products you acknowledge that you have read and understood the terms of this Privacy Policy, including how we use your personal information.

The data controller is responsible for collecting and using your personal information.  To comply with data protection legislation, the data controller will be the SEGA Entity with whom you contract for a Product. See **'Your questions and how to contact us'** section of this Privacy Policy for more details.

We reserve the right to update this Privacy Policy from time to time by changing it as it applies to your use of any of the Products.  The date of the current SEGA Privacy Policy is the Effective Date set out above. We want you to enjoy using our Products and urge you to follow common sense whenever disclosing personal information – in our Products or elsewhere.

**________________________________________________________________________**

## **Summary**

Our Privacy Policy will help explain what information we collect, how we use it and what options you have in relation to it. The key points of our Privacy Policy are provided below, however you can also learn more by simply following the link below or by continuing to scroll down:

## 1.Information we collect and receive

We collect personal information about you and the devices you use to access and interact with us and our Products. We collect:

(a) Registration information:  

| 

you give us when you sign up to access SEGA Products   
  
---|---  
  
(b) Billing information:  

| 

provided by you and/or third party stores  
  
(c) Technical and device information:

| 

information from your mobile or computer device when you use our Products  
  
(d) Feedback:

| 

your questions, suggestions or views on the Products  
  
(e) Third party information:

| 

information about your use of our Products that is shared with third party platforms and services connected with our Products  
  
Learn more

## 2.Our use of collected information

Collected information may be used in the following ways:

(a) Registration information:

(i) to create your profile and so you can access our Products;

(ii) to identify you when you sign-in;

(iii) to give you access to your user preferences;

(iv) to contact you for your views on our Products;

(v) to notify you of changes or updates to our Products; and

(vi) for marketing purposes, based on your communication preferences.

(b) Billing information:

(i) to verify your purchase of our Products and process any refunds;

(ii) to reply to any queries and questions and to resolve problems;

(iii) to carry out analysis and research to develop our Products; and

(iv) to protect you and the Products by seeking to detect and prevent fraud or other acts in breach of our user agreements or policies relevant to the Products.

(c)Technical and device information:

(i) to provide you with an optimal experience;

(ii) to understand how you interact with our Products

(iii) to provide Products you request; 

(iv) to measure and analyse the use and effectiveness of our Products;

(v) to understand which of your devices are using our Products and playing our videogames;

(vi) to provide safe and fair gaming environments;

(vii) to measure and analyse the use and effectiveness of our Products;

(viii) to customise and optimise the targeting of our advertising both on our Products and across other websites and Products;

(ix) to operate and improve our videogames; and

(x) to fix errors.

(d)Feedback:

(i) to reply to your questions or queries;

(ii) to record comments and information which you provide on our gaming forums; and

(iii) to conduct analysis and research to improve and develop the Products.

(e)Third party information:

(i) to enable us to provide tailored offers to you;

(ii) to facilitate sharing on social networks; and

(iii) to facilitate your gameplay.

Learn more

## 3.When we share information

We may share the information we collect about you (subject to the necessary security, contractual and transfer safeguards).  These are some of the partners we may share your personal information with:

(a) SEGA companies within the wider SEGA group.

(b) Platform operators such as Valve who operate the Steam digital download platform, Apple, Google Play and other partners who carry out various activities and services to support our Products.

(c) Marketing partners for marketing or promotions such as Mailchimp, based on your communication preferences.

(d) New owners or re-organised entities and their advisors in the event of a business restructure, sale, purchase or joint venture affecting our business.

(e) Where we are under a duty, are authorised by law or for law enforcement purposes.

Personal information may be transferred to other countries where SEGA or its service providers maintain operations. These countries may not have equivalent data protection laws to the country from where you access the Products.  
Learn more

## 4.Security and data retention

Your privacy is important to us and we place great importance on the steps we take, including technical and organisational measures to protect your information from unauthorised access and against unlawful processing, accidental loss, destruction and damage.

Your personal information will be kept by SEGA for the duration of your relationship with us and for as long as you use our Products and may be retained for a period after this time if it is necessary and relevant to our legitimate operations, our terms with you and in accordance with applicable laws.

Learn more

## 5.Your choices and rights

You have options and choices over how we use your personal information. You may be required to register or sign in to use or access some of our Products, and may need to provide personal information to create a user profile which is associated with your use of our Products. If you wish to amend the personal information that you use to access our Products, you can contact us using the details below.

By email at:                  [help@sega.co.uk](mailto:help@sega.co.uk)  
By telephone on:          +44 845 301 5502  
By writing to us at:

SEGA Europe Limited  
Customer Services  
27 Great West Road  
Brentford  
Middlesex  
TW8 9BW  
United Kingdom

If you sign up to our marketing communications, you will be asked to confirm your communication preferences and given the opportunity to unsubscribe at any time.

You can contact us directly with requests to correct, erase, restrict, object to, or move your personal information. If you do not want us to process and/or access your personal information, you may be unable to use some of our Products.

_Learn more_  

## 6.Children’s information

Protecting the privacy of young children is especially important to SEGA. For that reason, SEGA does not knowingly collect or maintain personal information or non-personally identifiable information from users under 13 years of age, other than as permitted by law in support of our internal operations.

Learn more  

## 7.Your questions and how to contact us

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy you can contact us.

Contact details

____________________________________________________________________

## **More information**

## 1.Information we collect

We collect personal information about you and the devices you use to access our Products and interact with us. We collect:

**(a) Registration information**

When you register or sign up to use our Products we collect information about you including your name, contact details, age, gender, personal preferences and additional information that you chose to provide. We may also collect your contact information so that you can sign-up to receive SEGA's marketing communications. As part of any required sign in to use our Products, we will verify the information that you use to log in.

You can also choose to sign-up for our Products using third party services such as your Facebook account in which case Facebook will ask you for permission to provide certain personal information such as your username, date of birth and contact details. Facebook may share this personal information with us subject to Facebook's privacy policy and the privacy settings of your Facebook account.  This may also enable Facebook and us to link your activities with your personal registration information at their site, and may include notifying your friends about your activities whilst using our Products. We may also use analytics technologies to link your online activities so that we can serve targeted ads.  Valve (the partner that operates the Steam digital download platform) may for example share anonymised Steam IDs with us to help optimise our offerings to you and to help us understand how you are using our Products. Again, if Valve shares this information with us it does so subject to its privacy policy, and the privacy settings of your Steam account.  If you sign-up via third party services you should visit the third party website and review their privacy policy and your registration profile or account to understand how your data is processed by them and to find out what your options are.

We do not control the information that is sent from your browser to third parties, including social media platforms, analytics companies and advertising networks which receive information in the normal course of your online activities.

**(b) Billing information**

We may collect payment information such as credit or debit card details (including expiration dates) and other billing information such as your name and address in order to verify your purchases, process any refund payments, contact you to resolve any product issues, and/or deliver Products to you. We may collect this information from you and/or third party stores that have been authorised to sell our Products.

**(c) Technical and device information**

We collect information from your web browsing activity about the way you use our Products. We may also collect information about you from the notifications or messages you post or send online as well as what you search for, look at and engage with. Information obtained from social features used on our Products or videogame software, such as forums and chat functionality, may be stored, copied or used by SEGA, the public, or third-party companies.

By accessing our Products, we may collect technical information from your mobile or computer device, for example your location information where you choose to share this with us, which devices are connected to the Internet, hardware settings, components of your devices, installed software, updates and plugins to facilitate the use of our Products. We may automatically collect information such as your operating system, Internet Protocol address, your browser type, browser language preferences and when, how often and how long you interact with our Products, websites and services. We also use software to enable us to provide safe and fair gaming environments for all users of our Products and when you log in to one of our Products, or make purchases.  We, and or our third party suppliers may use cookies and similar technologies, or collect data about your device(s) to create a device fingerprint of the components of your specific device(s).

See also our [Cookies Policy](http://www.sega.co.uk/cookiepolicy)

**(d) Feedback**

We will collect personal information from the messages and reviews you post on our social forums or on the _Games2Gether_ platform, and when you contact us, for example with a question, problem or comment. Telephone support through our customer services department is automated and we do not collect your personal information.  If you contact our customer services team by email or post, we will keep copies of your correspondence with us for as long as necessary to deal with your query.

**(e) Third party information**

We share information obtained from your use of our Products with third parties to provide you with an optimal experience, to facilitate use of the Products as advertised and to enable you to play our Products on various platforms.

## 2.How we use the information we collect

We use the personal information we collect for the following purposes:

**(a) Registration information**

Your registration information enables us to provide you with access to the Products and to supply the Products under the agreements we have with you. It helps us to authenticate your access, to contact you for your views and to notify you of important changes or updates to our Products.  

Where we have your consent and in accordance with your stated communication preferences, we may also contact you for marketing purposes to let you know by post, email, telephone, mobile or in-app messaging about our other products and services.

If you no longer want us to use your data in this way or generally change your mind about receiving marketing communications, you can unsubscribe at any time, either by using the unsubscribe option in the communication you receive or by changing your communication settings. Please note that we will retain a record of the user information when you unsubscribe from our marketing information for the legitimate purpose of ensuring that we do not contact you further in this way, during the period of your objection.

**(b) Billing information**

This information will enable us to verify your purchases with third party stores and to contact you in order to assist with resolving any problems with your purchases and to process any refund payments that you may be due.

We will also use and analyse information on transactions on your account for our legitimate interests by data matching or statistical analysis so that we can administer, support, improve and develop our business and to help us detect and prevent fraud, or other illegal activities, or acts prohibited by our terms of service or any policies applicable to the Products.

**(c) Technical and device information**

We analyse information about how you engage with our Products to understand how our Products are used and to provide you with an optimal gaming experience, such as by rolling out performance-optimising software updates for videogames.   We use anonymous data in order to analyse and produce statistics relating to the habits, usage patterns and demographics of users as a group or as individuals.  This allows us to deliver you personalised content, helps us understand the features of our Products that appeal to you and allows us to manage advertising, amongst other things.

When you interact or visit our websites, we may automatically collect information about you such as the type of internet browser or mobile device you use, any website from which you have come to any of the SEGA Products and your IP address (the unique address which identifies your device on the internet) and your operating system, which are automatically recognised by our web server.

We use internet log files to monitor traffic on our Products, resolve technical problems and to detect and prevent fraud.  We use these technologies to provide us with information, such as when an email is opened, or to develop statistics on the effectiveness of advertising or marketing on our websites. In some cases, working with third party partners, we use this information to send you ads for our Products based on your interests.

We also use technical and device information to operate and improve our videogames, enable online matchmaking, facilitate sharing, measure our effectiveness, set up and maintain accounts, identify and fix errors and to help keep online content fair and safe and to resolve related disputes.

**(d) Feedback**

We use your feedback to reply to your questions or queries, to provide customer support and resolve problems relating to any of our Products under the agreements that we have with you. We will also publish reviews that you submit to us for this purpose about the Products and will conduct analysis of feedback for the purpose of improving and developing the Products.

**(e) Third party information**

We share information obtained from your use of our Products with third parties to provide you with an optimal experience, to facilitate use of the Products as advertised and to enable you to play SEGA videogames on various platforms.

We may also work with advertising networks that serve advertisements into our Products, or the websites and products of third parties. Some of those advertisements may be personalised to your interests based on your activity and technical information and/or use cookies which are stored on your device.

Certain Products are currently supported by third party advertising partners that serve advertisements (“ **Third Party Advertisers** ”), including behavioural, location or interest based advertising (“ **Interest Based Advertising** ”) within our Products. These Third Party Advertisers use technology to serve the advertisements and link to them directly into the Products.  They may automatically receive your device ID, IP address or geo-location data when this happens. They may also use other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or web beacons) to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and to personalise the advertising content you see.

We may also bring you advertising content in a game, which you would traditionally see in a live game environment, for example perimeter advertising. For example, our Football Manager PC/Mac Product is currently supported by Bidstack, a platform that enables Third Party Advertisers to dynamically buy in-game native billboard space within video games.

## 3.When we share information

In delivering the Products to you, we may share your personal information with:

  * Companies within the SEGA group (which means SEGA Entities which are our parent and affiliated companies, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries and affiliates) who act for us for the purposes set out in this policy.
  * Third parties in order to undertake various activities or services on our behalf in supporting the Products. This includes payment processing providers facilitating credit and payment card transactions, website and application support and hosting providers for online videogame services and software downloads and providers for the delivery of promotional, digital advertising or other communications, such as MailChimp.
  * If our business enters into a joint venture, purchases or is sold to or merged with another business entity, your information may be disclosed or transferred to the target company, or new business partners or owners or their advisors.
  * We may use the information that you provide if we are under a duty to disclose or share your information in order to comply with (and/or where we believe we are under a duty to comply with) any legal obligation; or to enforce the relevant terms of service and any other agreement; or to protect our rights or the rights of third parties. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations such as credit agencies, law enforcement or government bodies or the courts in connection with a criminal investigation, suspected illegal activity, fraud prevention and detection or in legal proceedings.

We do not control information which is sent from your browser to third parties, including social media platforms, analytics companies and advertising networks that receive information in the normal course of your online activities.

Personal information may be transferred to other countries where SEGA or its service providers maintain operations. These countries may not have equivalent data protection laws to the country from where you access the Products or, in the case of transfers subject to European law, may not be subject to an adequacy decision by the European Commission (EC).   An adequacy decision is a decision taken by the EC establishing that a third country provides a comparable level of protection of personal data to that in the EU, through its domestic law or its international commitments.

Where SEGA transfers personal information it will seek to take account of any applicable legal obligations relevant to personal information transfers.  In the case of transfers of personal information out of the European Economic Area,  it will, in the absence of an EC adequacy decision relevant to the destination country, seek to rely on appropriate safeguards such as a valid Privacy Shield certification (in the case of a data transfer to a Privacy Shield certified US recipient -  <https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome>) or enter into appropriate EC approved standard contractual clauses relevant to personal data transfers between data controllers or between a data controller and a data processor, (see <http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/international-transfers/transfer/index_en.htm>).

## 4.Security and data retention

We place great importance on the steps we take, including physical, technical and organisational measures, to protect your information from unauthorised access and against unlawful processing, accidental loss, destruction and damage.

Where you have chosen a password which allows you to access any of the Products, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We advise you not to share your password with anyone. We will not be liable for any unauthorised transactions entered into using your username, personal information and/or password.

Your personal information will be retained by us for the duration of your use or access to our Products and may be retained for a period after this time as necessary and relevant to our legitimate operations, our terms with you and in accordance with applicable laws and obligations. This may include retention necessary to meet our tax reporting requirements as well as time required to enforce any obligations in our agreements, any game “sun-setting” requirements or to identify, issue or resolve legal proceedings. 

We may retain a record of your stated objection to the processing of your data, including in respect of an objection to receiving marketing communications, for the sole purpose of ensuring that we can continue to respect your wishes to not contact you further, during the term of your objection.

We will take appropriate steps to seek to destroy or permanently de-identify personal information at the point this information is no longer needed by us for our business or legal purposes.

For more information about exercising your rights with respect to our data processing activities, or if you no longer wish to use our Products, see details below about your choices and rights.

## 5.Your choices and rights

You have options and choices over how we use your information. We provide you with tools to access and update specific information relating to your use of the Products at any time. If you need to sign in to access certain Products, you can update and amend your key contact information directly.

We respect the rights you may have under applicable law to request access to your personal information and where applicable, to request to receive that information in a commonly used electronic format (or ask for this information to be provided in that format to a third party where feasible). You may also have the right under applicable law to request the correction or erasure of your personal information, to seek to object to the further processing under certain circumstances of your information or to request that the processing of specific information about you is restricted while we verify or investigate your concerns about this information.

If you remain unhappy with a response you receive, you can also refer the matter to your data protection supervisory authority (see <http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/bodies/authorities/index_en.htm>)

## 6.Children’s information

If SEGA learns that personal information of users under the age of 13 has been collected, other than for support of the internal operations, SEGA will take reasonable steps to remove such information. If you believe that we may have unintentionally collected personal information about your child who is under 13 years of age, you may contact us using the details provided below.

## 7.Your questions and how to contact us

If you have any questions or comments about this policy or our practices you can contact us:

By email at:                  [help@sega.co.uk](mailto:help@sega.co.uk)  
By telephone on:          +44 845 301 5502   
By writing to us at:

SEGA Europe Limited  
Customer Services  
27 Great West Road  
Brentford  
Middlesex  
TW8 9BW  
United Kingdom

You can also contact our Data Protection Officer at [dpo@sega.co.uk](mailto:dpo@sega.co.uk).
